AI is not waiting only for smarter code. It is waiting for a bigger power plug.
AIக்கு புத்திசாலி code மட்டும் போதாது. பெரிய power plug வேண்டும்.
The Kardashev scale is a civilization's power meter.
Kardashev scaleன்னா civilization-ன் power meter.
Today humanity sits around Type 0.73.
இன்று மனிதகம் சுமார் Type 0.73-ல் இருக்கிறது.
Type I sounds close, until you remember the scale is logarithmic.
Type I நெருக்கமா தோன்றும்; ஆனால் scale logarithmic.
That tiny jump means roughly 500 to 600 times more usable power.
அந்த சின்ன jump-க்கு 500 முதல் 600 மடங்கு usable power தேவை.
So AI stops being only a model story. It becomes a grid story.
அதனால் AI model story மட்டும் இல்லை; அது grid story.
Training, inference, cooling, backup: all of it needs electricity.
Training, inference, cooling, backup எல்லாம் electricity சாப்பிடும்.
IEA puts data centers at about 415 TWh in 2024.
IEA கணக்கில் 2024 data centres சுமார் 415 TWh பயன்படுத்தின.
Its base case points to roughly 945 TWh by 2030.
2030 base case? சுமார் 945 TWh.
Data centers can rise in months. Substations and firm power do not.
Data centres மாதங்களில் எழும்; substations அப்படி இல்லை.
Bitcoin's useful grid case is flexible demand, not magic.
Bitcoin-ன் நியாயமான grid case flexible demand; magic இல்லை.
The future may look like software; underneath it is turbines, transformers, copper, and cooling.
Future screen-ல் software போல இருக்கும்; கீழே turbines, transformers, copper, cooling.